JAMES GRAHAM DAVID

VENUE MANAGER

Food and Beverage Industry P: 079 017 388 56

E: jimmygrahamdavid@gmail.com

I am a hospitality professional with 14 years of experience within various areas of the industry. I enjoy working with people and creating relationships as well as drinks. I am knowledgeable on all areas of booze but excel in my beer knowledge as it a passion for me. I Would like the next step in my career to be in the beer industry.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Venue Manager/General Manager | Loop Roof Cocktail Bar & Garden | 2018-2019

Loop Roof 150 capacity cocktail bar located in the center of Melbourne's CBD, its focus being high end sustainable cocktails wild ingredients with an extensive spirit range and an ever-changing craft beer menu.

As the company's venue manager, I handle all day-to-day running of the venue. Reporting to Loop's managing director, I handle all rostering, stock ordering and control as well as budgets and hit my weekly KPI targets. Making sure all licensing was up to date and being adhered to.

Technical Assistant | Mr. Bitters | 2017-2019

Mr. biter is Melbourne's first bitters company. Dedicated to making unique flavor combinations for cocktails and other creations

Part time work for a bitters company helping with everything from manual labor, peeling citrus to helping steep the different comp0onents and then blending them to get the desired combination as well labeling and packaging of the final product.

Bar Manager | Loop Roof Cocktail Bar | 2017-2018

As the bar manager at Loop Roof, I managed a large bar and security team in a high-volume CBD venue. I work alongside the venue manager on all R&D for the venue, including heading up the craft beer side of the business and making sure all health and safety requirements were met. I also work with the bookings team on corporate events.

Venue Manager | Loop Project Space & Bar | 2015-2017

Loop Project Space and bar is 150 capacity bar/club/event space located in the center of Melbourne's CBD. Equipped with state of the art visual and audio equipment It provides a space for emerging artist to host events, from cinema viewings to club nights to ted talks.

As the venue manager, I oversaw the day to day running of the bar and project space. I was responsible for rostering the front-of-house team, all stock ordering and control, meeting with various product representatives as well as working service. I would also work closely with the bookings manager and arts coordinator to facilitate events in the project space.

Bar Supervisor | Loop Project Space & Bar | 2013-2015

As a bar supervisor, I managed most service shifts in the venue. My main duties would be to co-ordinate the events with the artists and event organisers as well as supervising a small bar team to ensure the bar was operational for both the events and for the public. I would also be charged with nightly reporting and cash

Bar/Venue Manager | Double Happiness Cocktail bar 2011-2012

Double happiness is a small cocktail bar located in the center of Melbourne's CB. Focusing on high turnover quality Asian themed cocktails and hip hop music.

I spent my first year of Australia in a small fast paced communist China themed cocktail bar. Double Happiness is small bar located in the CBD of Melbourne synonymous with the Melbourne hospitality scene. The goal was to keep a nice atmosphere for after work drinks during the week and on the weekends, keep an up-tempo vibe whilst serving cocktails at high volume.

Youth Theatre Member | Contact Theatre | Manchester | 1998-2009

Contact theatre is a space designed for creating and performing. It holds three different performance spaces and puts on work from local and nurtured talent to established pieces from across the globe.

I spent 11 years actively involved in Contact Theatre in many different capacities, ranging from acting, writing, hosting, facilitating workshops, ushering and more. Positions ranged from paid to volunteer roles.

QUALIFICATIONS

The University of Salford | Higher National Diploma | Media Performance | 2007-2009

Xaverian College | Rushholme | A-level | Media Performance | Drama | 2003-2006

REFERENCES

Adam Bunny | Director | Loop | 0405 320 225 | adambunny@netspace.net.au

Nathan Taylor | Venue Manager | Loop Roof Cocktail Bar | 0424 501 907

Miro Bellini | Brooklyn Beer Ambassador | Co-Founder Good Beer Week | 0401 235 540 | Mbellini@brooklynbrewery.com.au

Jacob Taylor | Owner | Mr Bitters | 0424 446 585 | Jacob@mr-bitters.com

EVENT / VOLUNTARY WORK

I was involved in setting up and co-ordinating events with different breweries for Melbourne's good beer week.

I volunteered for the Humans Rights Film Festival.

I performed/volunteered in Three bi-yearly contacting the world events that brought together twelve different theatre companies from six different countries for a week-long festival of workshops and peformance.

INTRESTS

In my downtime, I like to home brew, write (mostly scripts), go to the gym, watch football, coding (trying to teach myself on line) and sample the city's food and beverage scene.